Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to set up some of the blueprints for our boss character.
If we open them up and select the sprite and just make the source flipbook, our boss, Edo Animation.
Now our post is kind of small.
So I'm going to scale them up a bit.
I'll make this seven.
Then we want to make sure our bus fits within our capsule collision.
So I'm going to adjust it a bit or make it a bit wider.
I think that's good.
Next, if we select our animation component, make sure our boss uses the boss animation blueprint.
And if we head over to the land graph, we're ready to start coding our boss.
Okay, so the first thing we're going to do is make sure our boss character is always facing our player
character.
To save a bit of time, we can go to our mushroom blueprint.
And we can copy this handle rotation bit here.
So I'm going to copy these nodes.
And just pace them inside of my boss.
Then event.
I'm going to cool the handle rotation.
That way my boss will always be facing my player character.
So I drive up here and look for handle rotation and just right click on this is that and create a verbal
as later will be setting up a death system for our boss.
Now that we've handled the rotation for our boss, the next thing we're going to do is handle the movement
for our boss.
If we just drag off here and look for add movement input, under what direction?
Per value of one.
We want our boss to always move in the direction of our player character.
In order to do that, we can just do a quick calculation if we right click and forget player character.
And a struggle here.
And we'll get back to location.
When we right click and look or get actor location of our boss and just travel here and subtract.
And connect these nodes.
If we then do struggle here, I look for normalized.
So I'm going to explain what this does in a second.
But right now, it's just going to be easier to show you then if we just right click and look for split
pin and connect X into here.
So what we're doing is getting our location and subtracting it from our positive location.
Then we normalize this value and this was our post the correct direction to move in.
So let's go compile.
We'll just test this out and I'll explain this afterwards.
So I close this and drag in my boss.
I'm going to move them to their 20.
And we can just test this all out.
My boss is going to move towards me if I jump over them.
Then the boss will turn around and move towards me.
Nice.
Our boss will always move towards our player character.
So I'm not going to explain the notes inside of her.
If we open up our boss blueprint, what this normalise will do is convert this value to a magnitude
of one.
So if I just right click on this value and break the link here.
And right click and go spit trippin and just drag off X and look for print string and connect this node
into here and this into here.
If I could compile and play.
We can see this value is -1158 when I'm on this side and if I jump over the box, this body becomes
a positive value, although it's very high.
When we connect this value into the normalize, this normalize will basically make sure that this value
converts to a magnitude of one, and that will just get the direction of whatever my character is in.
So if I just break the link here and recombine the structure.
And hook up X into here and go compile and play.
We can see the value is minus around -0.99, which is kind of minus one.
And that will tell our boss to move towards the left.
And if I just jump over the boss, this value will become positive and we can see it's around 0.9.
This will tell our boss to move towards the right.
So because this value is between minus one and one, it allows our boss to move in the left or the right.
If we were to just use the values here, it may be a bit strange because normally when we use ADD movement
input, we use values of one or minus one.
If you remember in our play a character, when we hold the right button, we make the same value one.
And when we hold the left one, we make the scale minus one.
So by using a normalize, it kind of just helps convert this value to a magnitude of one, which helps
our boss move.
Hopefully that now makes sense to you.
While we're using this, we can just delete these nodes and connect this into here.
And the final thing we're going to do, I'm going to make it to my boss is flying.
So if we go to character movement and go to details, look for walking.
And by default, our character's normal mode is walking.
Just change this to be flying.
And then look for fly.
And just make sure this is checked and that will just ensure our boss can fly.
And now, if I go compile and close this.
Move up here and go play.
My boss is in the air.
Nice.
There's one more thing I want to do, and that is constrain my boss's movement to the Z axis.
That way they can't move up.
So if we just select our boss.
Good character movement.
And look for constrain.
And just check and train the plane.
And for the plane constraint, select Z.
And that will just make it so our boss can't move up or down.
So you kind of find like an area just a bit above the pack actor because that's where we want our boss
to be.